hi everybody my name is Luke Straton I
do sound and lights for doai this is my
world so I guess I'll start with my
Lighting World and then we'll go through
that and then move over here to audio um
I use a program called Grand Ma 2 uh on
PC uh it's designed to run on a big full
ligh console but basically I've uh I
used to be a software programmer so I I
programmed the whole desk onto a bunch
of uh mini boards so these are like this
is APC 20 and an APC 40 and inovation
Launchpad mini and an aai lpk25
um and they're you know they're usually
for a DJ or whatnot and I've kind of put
them all together inside of a DJ case
that treated as a lighting so uh grandom
a is pretty sophisticated software um so
I guess I kind of just quickly go
through how my board's laid out for
those nerds out there that are super
interested um the APC 20 is usually
colors um and the APC 40 is most
everything else it's got a few more uh
buttons and knobs so I've got some
effects and stuff but uh on my normal
page this is all this is my color grid
so the top here I've got solid colors
for the whole rig you can see here
up and they're kind of in order as they
are on the color wheel inside my lights
so that if I go from I know that red and
blue are close so I can do quick
movements without without seeing a jump
like if you go from Blue to to UV here
you see it jumps through the wheel and
then I have it sorted by fixture so if I
wanted to color the movers yellow and
the upstage wash blue down stage wash
purple I can I do that all manually down
now I've also got all that stuff on a
fader here like a a fade time fader if
you will so I can actually put this guy
all the way up dial a new look in and
then snap it down when I'm ready for
that look to hit uh I can also kind of
give it a fade so if I I want to go Fade
to Red here just put the fader up a
little bit the whole rig will slowly
turn um below that I got some Goos and
some other Page Changing buttons but
then on the bottom of each APC I have
this little Big Grid here I um I use use
what's I call it color theory so
basically I go from um from like magenta
and pink through red and through all the
colors of the rainbow up here back
through to Pink and then I try to go
bright looks medium looks and dark looks
so that way I can kind of hit a color
look without having to think about it so
for example if I want a bright yellow
look I can click this button and it'll
pop to a rig that has yellow in it
that's bright it may not be all yellow
but then if I want like a dark green
green look over here um now as far as
the actual color looks I I have a small
system where I've got them all named
with really creative names to help me
remember how to use them um for example
the one I just hit was called Alon I'm a
big Star Wars GE um you know over here
I've got fireplace which is kind of
obvious you know um but there's I've got
probably a hundred of different color
looks to help me kind of remember how I
use it
classic yet obvious ones are rainbow and
rosta yeah so that's mostly the 20 and
part of the 40 down here on the bottom
I've got faders on the left one the left
side faders here are usually for what
are called specials so I can Spotlight
on a member of the band um but on a
bigger rig where I've got a lot of
conventional lights sometimes I'll have
to use some of these faders to control
the red Park
Hands the second set here are some
movement fers so if I want to make the
lights move in a certain kind of
Direction I
can now over on the on APC 40 I got a
bunch of other stuff uh this top row
here is positions so I could you know
point the lights down or make it uh X's
or uh Point them at the wall um but
those all key off this fader here so if
I want them to fade slowly to down I
just put this fader that way and hit
down and it goes it's kind of fun I got
a lot of positions and I got some double
stacked positions so if I hit the button
twice it goes to a different position um
what else I so this this little button
grid here are my strobes so I've got
like a Paran you know wash strobe and
then a mover strobe uh I've got a all
white strobe uh and then I've got a
button called freak out which is
basically color Spin and prism it's the
works uh then the next little grid
section down here are all my chases and
those key off the fader too so I can
kind of play things
uh along with the
band um over here are Iris buttons to
kind of change the shape of the beam you
can see small Iris or big Iris or you
can Frost it all the way
out um and then some you know kind of
color effects all kinds of stuff
scattered in here got some uh some Goos
over here which for those not in the
industry those are like the shape that
the light makes to you'll see this is a
triangle or a circle
some
lines um as far as my knobs I got these
are mostly all
movements and then things like prism
speed Gobo scroll speed Gobo rotation
speed and color
speed um then you know I get asked a lot
what what all is going on I've he people
see the keyboard they like you got a
keyboard what you you play notes back
there and these are all bumps for the
rig so I've got some I can black out the
rig and I can bump in the LEDs for all
these different colors or if I've got
the rig on it'll still it'll shift the
rig to that color but they're temporary
so when I let go they kind of go back to
it I've got some blackout
bumps and some uh turn on
bumps some some wipes
here and um yeah that kind of stuff so I
guess that's pretty much my light rig
more or less I guess I should talk real
quick about what we're using our touring
rig is six Elation Platinum spot 5 RS
it's a it's a pretty uh relatively cheap
bright fixture that moves pretty quick
uh and it's kind of my main Workhorse so
all my programming that I have for those
5 hours I'll walk into a bigger room and
and I'll do what's called clone I'll
clone that programming from our
light then we also have a bunch of LED
uh LEDs that we have so uh this is my
audio world yeah so we uh we tour with a
pronus uh Studio live uh
2442 uh it's 24 Channel console um and
uh for years we tour with my 16 channel
one but we finally grew out of that one
and this board gives me a few more
options we get to have a few more things
in Stereo make a few more
drums um I'm running this guy with a
through fire wire 800 right into our
MacBook Pro uh and on this I'm running
two pieces of software I'm running um
the main control program which is called
universal control uh which is great for
kind of uh seeing spectrographs of
what's going on with the audio but then
also um it's what lets the guys control
their in your monitor mixes over their
their iPhones um this program is the is
the key for that happen um the other
thing I use is uh prus capture 2 which
is just a really simple audio recording
program it basically records everything
that comes into this board before I've
even done anything to it to the hard
drive so no matter what I do with the
mix if I get creative or or something's
too loud this will capture it before
that so if I go back to mix a show and
release it online it's
already it's it's unprocessed pre pre-
Dynamics
inq um it's a great console um one of my
thing things I love about it I mean a
lot of digital consoles have a lot of
these features now but um when I first
made the switch you know every channel
has uh 4 band parametric EQ uh
compression um key Gates or expanders
limiters it's just it lets me really
dial in every single channel so that I'm
not necessarily worried about each
individual channel so much more I can
just focus on the
overall um everybody's on in now except
for Rob who's he's got his own um uh QSC
monitor so we lets us fall into any room
and kind of be able to put the same sh
on um yeah think that's pretty much it
you know I could go into the the
microphone cabinet that we tour with but
I think I'll save that for more of the
audio nerd type
so yeah any questions feel free to email
me at ldap
pod.com and hope to see you guys at a
show
[Music]